Peter Bishop

720-938-6873 ~ pjb.den@gmail.com ~ https://github.com/Pierre81385 https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-bishop-46a51597/ CUNY Baruch College ~ DU Full-Stack Bootcamp

PROFILE

Full stack web developer with combined experience in the service industry and tech startups providing a balanced background of skills both customer facing and technical. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from DU Coding Bootcamp, and a BBA from CUNY Baruch college with an emphasis on Economics. Strengths in client interaction, team collaboration, and a passion for backend development.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTLM5, SQL, SWIFT4

Applications: GitHub, MySQL, Xcode

Tools: Express, Node, Handlebars, JQuery, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Favorite Recipes, Role: Backend developer, responsible for developing routes, creating backend to front end connections.

- https://github.com/JaredWilliam97/Favorite-Recipes
- https://murmuring-river-43433.herokuapp.com

Summary - A collaborative project developing a full stack web application that functions as a blog posting site.

Tools - HTML, CSS, Bootswatch, Javascript, Node.js, Express Sessions, Sequelize, Handlebars, and MySql.

Weather Dashboard, Role: Sole developer

- https://github.com/Pierre81385/weatherDashboard-HW6
- Https://pierre81385.github.io/weatherDashboard-HW6

Summary - A web application to find current and 5 day forecasts of weather in cities around the world.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, and OpenWeatherAPI

EXPERIENCE

General Manager, Sushi-Rama, Denver, CO - June 2019 to August 2020

As the General Manager I was responsible for overseeing all aspects of restaurant operations. I managed staffing, oversaw BOH and FOH ordering and inventiory, and was responsible for balancing daily and weekly checkout, entering invoices, and conducting payroll. I was also responsible for designing specialty cocktails and working closely with the kitchen manager to design cost effective offerings to drive sales, clear inventory, and drive awareness of our offerings.

Key Accomplishments:

- Steadily increased year-over-year sales, and tracked this progress by developing a portfolio of spreadsheets to track and manage profit and loss, weekly inventory, cost of goods sold, product mix, and sales by guest count.
- Took charge of the basic administration of the company's web presence. Customizing sites for Sushi-rama, Osaka Ramen, and The Empire lounge. Developing signage, updating menus, and creating custom QR codes to adapt to the pandemic.
- Obtained the ServSafe Manager certification.

Bartender, Mile High Spirits, Denver, CO - July 2015 to June 2019

As a bartender at MHS, I served in a high volume environment, developing positive customer relationships, ensuring customers were responsibly served and received consistent craft cocktails.

Key Accomplishments:

- Additionally worked in production canning, bottling, and responsible for making the Denver Dry Gin.
- Lead the distillery tour program, educating guests, explaining the distillation process, and leading guided tastings.
- Obtained TIPS and Merchant Guard licenses.

QA Analyst, Data Connect Corp, Denver, CO - July 2012 to February 2018 As a QA Analyst, I tested software release features on iOS, Windows, and cloud based systems relating to an event management product. Working with JIRA for case management. Ran all database scripts on client databases to move them from testing to show ready.

Key Accomplishments:

- Assisted with staff and equipment logistics, hiring just-in-time staff, developing hardware inventory systems, and conducting regular training to improve staff skills.
- Traveled regularly to events as a Team Leader, overseeing hardware and software deployment, executing over \$655,000 in show day services across more than 30 events per year. Provided live demos and training on our software and services to groups as large as 300, and custom reports on demand with SQL database queries to compile event statistics.

EDUCATION

CUNY Baruch College BBA in Economics, 2008

University of Denver, Full Stack Web Development Certificate, 2021